Register of the Gleb Struve Papers 1810-1985
Hoover Institution Archives
- CORRESPONDENCE, ALPHABETICAL, 1965-1985
  - Alekseev, A., 1965-1978 (Folder 2)
  - B., A. N., 1979 (Folder 3)
  - Baboreko, Aleksandr, 1967-1969 (Folder 4)
  - Chukovskaia, Lydia, Feb. 1981 (Folder 5)
  - Kagan-Kans, Eva, 1965-1966 (Folder 6)
  - Kralin, Mikhail, 1973-1974 (Folder 7)
  - Leikina-Svirskaia, Vera, 1981-1983. Includes miscellaneous writings, 1981-1983 (Folder 8)
  - Lubiannikova, Ekaterina, 1981-1985. Includes Marina Tsvetaeva programs (Folder 9)
  - Meilakh, Mikhail, 1976-1977 (Folder 10)
  - Pasternak, Eugene, 1975-1976 (Folder 11)
  - Pinskii, L., 1973 (Folder 12)
  - Vitkovskii, E., 1978 (Folder 13)
- MICROFILM 1931-1937 (Microfilm cabinet)
  Arranged by subject.
  - Mandel'shtam, Osip
    - "Novye stikhi", includes "Pervaia voronezhskaia tetrad'" and "Vtoraia voronezhskaia tetrad'", 1931-1937, typescript with corrections in hand. Labelled "Thomson typescript" in Gleb Struve's hand (Reel Reels 1-2)
    - Unidentified typescript from Harvard University Library (Reel Reel 3)
  - Grossman, Vasilii, Vse techet, typescript, n.d. (Reel Reel 4)
  - Kozlovskii, Prince Petr, miscellaneeous correspondence, n.d. (Reel Reel 5)
- PHONOTAPES 1958-1971 (Tape cabinet)
  Sound recordings of speeches and lectures delivered by Gleb Struve and of Gleb Struve reading his poetry; and phonotape of Anna Akhmatova reading her poetry
  - Akhmatova, Anna
    - Sound recording of the ceremony conferring an Honorary Doctorate at Oxford University 1965, Use copy reference number: 85018_a_0006660 (Phonotape Tape 1)
  - Struve, Gleb
    - Phonotapes
      - Sound recording of Gleb Struve speech "Boris Pasternak and Doctor Zhivago"December 1, 1958, Use copy reference number: 85018_a_0006661 (Phonotape Tape 2)
        Struve also speaks about poetry, and Pasternak's place in Russian literature. Given at the University of California, Berkeley.
      - Sound recording of Gleb Struve speech "The Trial Ends -- What Next?" March 18, 1966, Use copy reference number: 85018_a_0006663 (Phonotape Tape 3)
        Struve speaks about the trial of Andrei Sinyavsky and Yuli Daniel. This lecture was delivered at the Center for Slavic and East European Studies, Berkeley.
      - Sound recording of Gleb Struve speech about Anna Akhmatova 1967 (?), Use copy reference number: 85018_a_0006665 (Phonotape Tape 4)
        Struve speaks about the poetry of Anna Akhmatova, including his impressions from meeting her. At the end, he reads her poetry in Russian.
      - Sound recording of Gleb Struve lecture "Akhmatova i N. V. Nedobrovo" April 4, 1971, Use copy reference number: 85018_a_0006668 (Phonotape Tape 5)
        Struve delivers, in Russian, a talk on Anna Akhmatova. He is introduced by a man speaking English. This talk was given at the University of Toronto.
      - Sound recording of Gleb Struve speech at the University of Toronto commencement June 2, 1971, Use copy reference number: 85018_a_0006670 (Phonotape Tape 6)
      - Sound recording of Anna Akhmatova reading her poetry undated, In Russian. Use copy reference number: 85018_a_0006671 (Phonotape Tape 7)
    - Sound recording of Gleb Struve reading his poetry (phonotape copy) undated (Phonotape Tape 8)
- PHOTOGRAPHS
  - 150 prints and 13 negatives of Gleb Struve., 1908-1985 (Folder C)
    Includes family photographs and group pictures with friends and colleagues.
  - 5 prints related to Nikolai Nedobrovo, includes portrait prints of Nedobrovo, his wife and a group photograph; 3 negatives and 2 prints of portraits of Nikolai Gumilev; 1 negative and 4 prints related to Boris Anrep; 4 portrait prints of Vera Znamenskaia., undated (Box D)
  - 6 prints related to Brois Pasternak, includes informal snapshots and group photograph with Ehrenburg, Blok and Tikhonov; 1 print of portrait of Salomeia Andronikova-Halpern; 5 prints of Marina Tsvetaeva, including print of portrait, 1922; 1 portrait print of Fedor Sologub; 1 portrait print of Aleksei Remizov. (Box E)
  - 3 portrait prints of Osip Mandel'stam, 1930-1906. 1 print of Mandel'shtam;s identity card; 1 group of portrait of Akhmatova with the Mandel'shtam family, 1930; 1 group portrait of Akhmatova, Chulkov and Mandel'shtam; 1 group portrait of Akhmatova, Chulkov and Mandel'shtam's portrait by Lev Bruni; 2 photocopies of pencil portraits of Mandel'shtam; 1 portrait print of Nadezhda Mandel'shtam inscribed to Bleb Struve; 4 negatives. (Box G)
  - 1 print of unidentified drawing by Maksimil'ian Voloshin; 2 group portraits including Voloshin; 2 prints of Voloshin's study; 1 print of a watercolor signed Moreiko, 1973; 3 prints of portraits of Prince Petr Kozlovskii; 2 portrait prints of R.M. Rilke. (Box H)
  - 1 group portrait including Bezimenskii, Kamenskii, Efimov and kukreniks; 1 print of Nekso chatting with Tretiakov; 1 print of Serafimovich; 1 print of A.S. Novikov-Priboi; 1 print of Mayakovskii; 1 print of L. Leonov; 4 prints and 2 negatives of IU. Oksman; 2 prints of E. Evtushenko; 3 prints of A. Solzhenitsyn; 2 portrait prints of I. Brodskii, 3 prints of D. Klenovskii; 2 prints of V. Morkovin; 10 prints of paintings by M. Khrisagonov; 1 print of V. Romanovich; 5 prints of IU. Dobkevich; 9 prints related tot he Fr. Ewshliman group; 1 print of A. Ginsburg; 1 print of memorial to Sir Bernard Padres., undated (Box I)
  - circa 140 prints related to Gleb Struve's literary correspondents and colleagues, including A. Boem, S. L. Frank, V. Pereleshin, L.L'vov and V.L. Burtsev and the editorial board of "Za svobodu", undated (Box J)
  - 30 prints related to miscellaneous political figures active before the revolution and in emigration, including members of the Duma, the Imperial Family, V. V. Shul'gin and P. Savitskii., 1890's-1970 (Box K)
  - circa 65 prints and 6 negatives related to Russia., undated (Folder m L)